Erol Bicer, Ph.D.Nuclear Engineer



- erolbicer@live.com
- +82-10-7497-0705
- www.erolbicer.com
- in LinkedIn/erolbicer
- R⁶ ResearchGate/Erol-Bicer
- GitHub/nucerl
- South Korea

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent

Turkish - Fluent

Korean — Conversational

SYSTEM CODES

RELAP5 | MARS-KS | SPACE

CONTAINMENT CODES

GOTHIC | CAP

SEVERE ACCIDENT

MELCOR

CFD CODES

OpenFOAM | CUPID

CODING LANGUAGES

PYTHON | MATLAB | FORTRAN | C++ | HTML/CSS

TOOLS

ERP | Microsoft Project | Trello |
Jira | Git | PCTRAN | SNAP |
Origin | Salome | DOS/UNIX |
ParaView | CATIA | Mathcad

PROFILE

I have over nine years of experience specializing in conducting comprehensive safety analyses for various nuclear power plants, using advanced system and computational fluid dynamics codes. My expertise encompasses successfully developing, leading, and completing international projects through effective collaboration with diverse multinational and multicultural teams.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FNC Technology Co., Ltd.

Manager | Overseas Business Team 2024/11 – present | South Korea

Manager | Thermal-Hydraulics Technology 2023/10 – 2024/11 | South Korea

Associate Manager | Thermal-Hydraulics Technology 2019/08 – 2023/10 | South Korea

Assistant Manager | Department of Thermal-Hydraulics Research 2016/01 – 2019/08 | South Korea

Bil-Plas Industry and Trade Co., Ltd., R&D Engineer ☑ 2013 – 2014 | Ankara, Türkiye

EDUCATION

Nuclear Engineering, Ph.D., Seoul National University

2024 | Seoul, South Korea

Nuclear Power Plant Engineering, M.Sc., KINGS ≥ 2016 | Ulsan, South Korea

Nuclear Energy Engineering, B.Sc., Hacettepe University ≥ 2013 | Ankara, Türkiye

LATEST PROJECTS

[SMR] Small and Micro Modular Reactors Technology Analyses Project Development and Management (APM)

[MSR] Development and Analysis of Fuel Salt Leakage Behavior in Discharge System Shell

Project Development and Management (APM)

[PGSFR] Prototype Gen-IV Sodium-Cooled Fast Reactor Analysis [EUR] APR1000 PAFS Standard Design Development and EUR Certification Support

CERTIFICATES AND AWARDS

Professional Engineer, KENCA

International Marketing, Business and Intelligence, ATO Modeling and Computation of Multiphase Flows, ETH International Atomic Energy Agency Fellowship, IAEA Full Academic Scholarship, KINGS

Addition Contracting, 191100

Nuclear Industry Association of Turkey, Board of Directors ☑

Turkish Chamber of Commerce in Korea, Co-Founder ☑

PERSONAL VENTURES

Hacettepe Rugby Club, Founder ☑